Charles Pinfold Papers
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress
Charles Pinfold Papers 1641-1767 (bulk 1756-1766)
MSS99002
Pinfold, Charles, 1709-1788
11 items
11 containers
2.2 linear feet
Manuscript Division, Library of Congress Washington, D.C.
Governor of Barbados. Bound materials relating to Pinfold's governorship of Barbados, 1756-1766, including minutes of the proceedings of the president and council of Barbados, transcripts of the island's general assembly, letterbooks, royal orders and instructions, and printed acts of the assembly.
Selected Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the LC Catalog. They are grouped by name of person or organization, by subject or location, and by occupation and listed alphabetically.
People
Pinfold, Charles, 1709-1788.
Places
America--Politics and government--18th century.; Barbados--History--18th century.; Barbados--Politics and government--18th century.; Great Britain--Colonies--America--Administration.; North America--History--Colonial period, ca. 1600-1775.; West Indies--History--18th century.; West Indies--Politics and government.
Occupations
Governors--Barbados.
Provenance
The papers of Charles Pinfold, governor of Barbados, were purchased by the Library of Congress in 1905.
Access and Restrictions
The papers of Charles Pinfold are open to research. Researchers are advised to contact the Manuscript Reading Room prior to visiting. Many collections are stored off-site and advance notice is needed to retrieve these items for research use.
Scope and Content Note
The papers of Charles Pinfold (1709-1788) span the years 1641-1767, with the bulk of the material concentrated in the period 1756-1766 while Pinfold was governor of Barbados. Included are letterbooks, minutes of the proceedings of the president and council of Barbados, minutes of the council, transcripts of the island's general assembly, royal orders and instructions, and printed acts of the assembly, some of which predate Pinfold's governorship. The period treated covers the Seven Years War between England and France, 1754-1763, known in the American colonies as the French and Indian War, encompassing political events in the West Indies and also the North American continent.
Arrangement of the Papers
This collection is organized in bound volumes by type of material..
Container List
- Minutes of the president and council, Oct. 28, 1735, to July 15, 1736; with a list of fees collected in the courts and executive offices (Box 1)
- Transcript of the journal of the proceedings of the general assembly, Aug. 31, 1756, to Mar.18, 1765; and the committee of public accounts, May 17, 1757, to Dec. 8, 1763 (Box 2)
- Minutes of the council (Box 3)
  - Vol. 1, Aug. 16, 1756, to May 6, 1760 (Box 3)
  - Vol. 2, May 28, 1760, to 27 May, 1766 (Box 4)
- Royal orders and instructions, signed by the king, issued to Governor Pinfold, Mar. 16, 1756; minutes of the meetings of the president and commander in chief in council, July 15, 1766, to May 27, 1767; and extracts from the council books, Oct. 13, 1641, to Nov. 27, 1739 (Box 5)
- Letterbooks of Governor Pinfold (Box 6)
  - Vol. 1, Aug. 12, 1756, to May 24, 1766 (Box 6)
  - Vol. 2, Aug. 14, 1756, to Jan. 6, 1764 (Box 7)
  - Vol. 3, Feb. 2, 1764, to July 10, 1766 (Box 8)
- Acts of Assembly, Passed in the Island of Barbadoes, from 1648 to 1718. Printed London, 1732; also contains, in manuscript, laws passed from 1739 to 1752 (Box 9)
- Acts Passed in the Island of Barbadoes, from 1643 to 1762, inclusive. With an Index and Abridgement. Printed London, 1744 (Box 10)
- Acts of assembly, passed in the island of Barbados, in manuscript, 1762-1764 (Box 11)